# DAMIAN ŚWISTOWSKI

## PERSONAL INFORMATION

email damian@swistowski.org

phone +44 7402 64 28 69

I am software developer with 15+ years of experience in the industry. I have worked on a wide range of projects, from small web applications to large enterprise systems. I am a polyglot programmer, but I have a particular interest in python, typescript and distributed systems.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

2023-Present Software Engineer

Genie AI London Work on backend services, improve testability.

Automate content delivery pipeline, automate building dependencies

Implementing integrations with various exchanges and blockchains (Deribit, OKX, Solana)

Extending portfolio of calculated asset metrics, make sure they are calculated in efficient way

python • fastapi • k8s • elasticsearch • postgresql • react • typescript

2022-2023 Staff Engineer

Babylon Health London

Design and build 3rd generation of Babylon conversation platform (async messaging)

Design GraphQL API for north traffic

Design Rest API for west-east traffic

Create Conversation Platform Test Runner, a tool for defining requirements and tests in Domain Specific Language. COpTeR provides abstraction to have stable acceptance tests for whole product, with fraction less integration with Babylon testing infrastructure

python • fastapi • k8s • elasticsearch • kafka • react native • typescript

2020-2022 Engineering Manager

Babylon Health London Manage 3-6 direct reports, depending on the team size

Work closely with stakeholders and product managers to define roadmap and priorities

Replace 1st generation of the Babylon conversation platform with 2nd generation without a big bang

Make sure SSDLC is followed and that the team is following best practices

Put pressure on the business to make sure my team have enough time to not cumulate too much technical debt

Put pressure on the team to make sure what they deliver is aligned with the client's needs

Do pairing sessions with team members to make sure knowledge is shared

Build state storage format for conversation state to with delta layers allowing undo peration. The state is strongly typed and schema changes were handled automatically and in a safe manner

python • flask • k8s • postgres • redis • kafka

2019-2000 Senior Software Engineer

Babylon Health London Part of the design team which created the migration plan from 1st generation of the Babylon conversation platform (monolith) to 2nd generation (microservices)

Create various CLI tools used by the team and other teams to make integration with the Conversation Platform easier

python • flask • k8s • postgresql • redis • kafka

Senior Software Engineer

B<sub>2</sub>C<sub>2</sub> London Created the Trade History collecting system

REST API crawler was created as cloud task, raw data were processed with a set of stateless procedures

python  $\cdot$  aws  $\cdot$  lambda  $\cdot$  sqs  $\cdot$  elasticache

2017-2019 Senior Python Developer

Springer Nature London

Build and iterate internal CI/CD system and tooling

Migrate legacy code to python 3

Define build pipelines used by other teams with an easy definition of build steps

Develop tooling for Cloud Foundry deployments

python · OpenStack · celery

2015-2017 Senior Engineer

Shortlist San Francisco (remote) Developing the backend for the workforce management platform project

Cooperate with frontend engineers to define usable REST API

Design and implement a data model for the system

python • django • postgresql • django rest framework • javascript • angular

2012-2015 Senior Python Developer

ZedMedia Globally (REMOTE) Maintain a Django-based application

Implement a scoring algorithm for articles to be present in a different part of the service

Extend and maintain database models

Create tools for easy A/B tests

python • django • postgresql • javascript • perl

2010-2012 Senior Python Developer

Intelligent Elite BARCELONA

Create an A/B testing suite with detailed statistics about user behaviour

Improve the mailing system

 $python \cdot django \cdot postgresql \cdot solr \cdot mongodb$ 

2008-2010 Python Developer

*OMS* Bielsko-Biała, Design and implement a production management system

POLAND Managing a team of 4 junior engineers

python • django • mysql

2007-2008 PHP Junior developer

Gery Design Wrocław, Poland Migrate old PHP projects to the Django framework

Maintenance and optimization of existing projects

php • javascript • python • django • None

## **EDUCATION**

2005 - 2007 The University of Silesia, Katowice

Master of Computer Science

· Computer Science and Materials Science

Thesis: Particle Swarm Optimization in funding function minimum

2002 - 2005 The University of Silesia, Katowice

Bachelor of Computer Science

· Computer Science and Materials Science

Thesis: Developing an electronic repository for undergraduate theses

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

2006 Comparative Study: ACO and EC for TSP

kaeiog

The paper concentrates on the Traveling Salesman Problem solved by evolutionary and ACO algorithms

## OTHER INFORMATION

Communication

2019 · PyCon UK

Skills

c?attrs how use it with rest microservices

Interests Hiking · Social dancing · Cooking · Video Games